{"cards":[{"mId":"3d12d9e0-3f59-4114-837e-0b141e1d9b2c","mCardType":"text","mFront":"not normal for the human body","mBack":"abnormal"},{"mId":"00a7b3fd-64a7-4040-8c16-032390571652","mCardType":"text","mFront":"pain that won\u0027t go away","mBack":"ache"},{"mId":"225a9193-f0c8-4500-879f-0d5b74f9255f","mCardType":"text","mFront":"quick to become severe/bad","mBack":"acute"},{"mId":"cceaefeb-91d3-47b9-8070-5fd10122a0b6","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a body\u0027s abnormal reaction to certain foods or environmental substances (eg causes a rash)","mBack":"allergy"},{"mId":"6c1ed8a5-2967-4e39-ae80-53f99ca84ded","mCardType":"text","mFront":"emergency vehicle that rushes people to a hospital","mBack":"ambulance"},{"mId":"ba68ef98-7c0a-40c6-88e7-0ce05cad20ee","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a condition that causes people to lose their memory","mBack":"amnesia"},{"mId":"e4b68a2a-1a90-4fbb-b6c4-4a9e832e7cc4","mCardType":"text","mFront":"permanent removal of a limb","mBack":"amputation"},{"mId":"f80d213a-9c5c-4cf1-ba11-4065fb91eaf4","mCardType":"text","mFront":"occurs when the body doesn\u0027t have enough red blood cells","mBack":"anaemia"},{"mId":"19eb142f-e9a0-4674-8f84-aebd26c46717","mCardType":"text","mFront":"medication that kills bacteria and cures infections","mBack":"antibiotics"},{"mId":"9d017fa1-2345-4474-9ec7-c2abdc511661","mCardType":"text","mFront":"medication that helps relieve anxiety and sadness","mBack":"anti-depressant"},{"mId":"714392af-7364-4aa1-a6ba-4814c38678c3","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a scheduled meeting with a medical professional","mBack":"appointment"},{"mId":"d6872cce-4e67-4d39-900b-5edd38672986","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a disease that causes the joints to become swollen and crippled","mBack":"arthritis"},{"mId":"6211bd4b-af82-40e3-9834-c7ac8dbd547b","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a condition that causes a blockage of the airway and makes it difficult for a person to breathe","mBack":"asthma"},{"mId":"8c3755cd-6337-4e2e-ae3b-2f1db329c958","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a disease-causing organism","mBack":"bacteria"},{"mId":"125875e0-65ac-4556-8ece-5e07969c14b4","mCardType":"text","mFront":"wounds that develop on a patient\u0027s body from lying in one place for too long","mBack":"bedsore"},{"mId":"9908b075-6626-4880-a730-c1d1258368a0","mCardType":"text","mFront":"not harmful (not cancerous)","mBack":"benign"},{"mId":"05fb8183-ecff-4ad9-9220-e04177cc498f","mCardType":"text","mFront":"removal of human tissue in order to conduct certain medical tests","mBack":"biopsy"},{"mId":"0316ce5b-3e47-4b8f-8ac5-2c0537c4c299","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the amount of red and white blood cells a person has","mBack":"blood count"},{"mId":"855db91d-d4f7-44e5-985a-92fc90fd101f","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a person who gives blood to a blood bank or other person","mBack":"blood donor"},{"mId":"6082b252-4905-4f83-8d92-1b4c6b58340a","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the rate at which blood flows through the body (high/low)","mBack":"blood pressure"},{"mId":"24c94e08-5ea3-478b-85b7-defb851216e4","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a device that holds injured body parts in place","mBack":"brace"},{"mId":"1df72d10-1536-460c-ad6b-d4e86eae67aa","mCardType":"text","mFront":"position of an unborn baby in which the feet are down and the head is up","mBack":"breech"},{"mId":"cd8f8233-72f8-4c57-8e78-2e39a930ce91","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a bone that is divided in two or more pieces as a result of an injury","mBack":"broken"},{"mId":"9998b360-1a44-4ba6-b5ac-1bb78508d9d0","mCardType":"text","mFront":"injured body tissue that is visible underneath the skin","mBack":"bruise"},{"mId":"c70fa97f-7b05-4a1c-89c4-94d8dfe9a727","mCardType":"text","mFront":"procedure that involves removing a baby from its mother through an incision in the woman\u0027s lower abdomen","mBack":"Caesarean section"},{"mId":"fb7f518d-6b3b-4dec-8713-3f6c7e4e4b5e","mCardType":"text","mFront":"disease caused by the uncontrollable growth of cells","mBack":"cancer"},{"mId":"3118d2a4-7910-4130-8a28-0799e228dcbd","mCardType":"text","mFront":"restoring a person\u0027s breath and circulation","mBack":"cardiopulmonary resuscitation "},{"mId":"0e4b7a0b-59f1-44ee-b52b-c65e68be4498","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a hard bandage that is wrapped around a broken bone to keep it in place","mBack":"cast"},{"mId":"cac3c8df-4e04-4d5b-8b22-6522b89dcc9f","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a place where loved ones can go to pray for a patient\u0027s recovery;","mBack":"chapel"},{"mId":"3766d6b6-bf29-4f9d-a658-f55133d3813e","mCardType":"text","mFront":"type of treatment used on cancer patients","mBack":"chemotherapy"},{"mId":"6a933107-6b89-4392-8f68-9f56597433e4","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a virus commonly contracted by children, characterized by itchy spots all over the body","mBack":"chickenpox"},{"mId":"51c54249-399c-4bf3-8ec9-7a374cb69af4","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a person who determines the cause of death after a person dies","mBack":"coroner"},{"mId":"fd990cbd-8a0f-45c4-9256-de073dec01c2","mCardType":"text","mFront":"requiring immediate and constant medical attention","mBack":"critical condition"},{"mId":"1a9a813e-877e-4fe9-954c-eb38cbc63893","mCardType":"text","mFront":"objects that people with injured legs or feet use to help them walk","mBack":"crutches"},{"mId":"c33c908e-9111-45ae-9db0-ac8c4d2b491f","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a sac in the body-tissue filled with fluid (sometimes diseased)","mBack":"cyst"},{"mId":"6946bf3d-5eec-40ed-a672-c504746b3e4a","mCardType":"text","mFront":"unable to hear","mBack":"deaf"},{"mId":"02a1e833-546e-4457-988e-86189fc73196","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a lack of something necessary for one\u0027s health","mBack":"deficiency"},{"mId":"2c2cf864-95e6-441f-975e-fe7f0103bf56","mCardType":"text","mFront":"in need of water","mBack":"dehydrated"},{"mId":"13f0a60f-6f6b-4134-8ad5-5ac717607882","mCardType":"text","mFront":"loss of mental capacity","mBack":"dementia"},{"mId":"dc1e4683-d397-4018-a5d3-32543e736564","mCardType":"text","mFront":"type of disease typically involving insulin deficiency","mBack":"diabetes"},{"mId":"949fd02d-af7d-446e-a208-cedcd46219b1","mCardType":"text","mFront":"medical explanation of an illness or condition","mBack":"diagnosis"},{"mId":"3dd15383-30d1-4f3c-99dd-32c19e5b921e","mCardType":"text","mFront":"experiencing pain","mBack":"discomfort"},{"mId":"affd3d83-a3bf-45a6-b9a9-e13c07a9b588","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a medical disorder that is harmful to a person\u0027s health","mBack":"disease"},{"mId":"550a679f-9f6e-47b7-8895-f1089f17257b","mCardType":"text","mFront":"when a bone is temporarily separated from its joint","mBack":"dislocated"},{"mId":"3a3a4d29-c409-496d-8a9e-4a581c961c0c","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a medical problem that needs immediate attention","mBack":"emergency"},{"mId":"49b61582-e667-4d57-84a8-b906bddbb8f6","mCardType":"text","mFront":"on the outside","mBack":"external"},{"mId":"8b60fb13-e11f-44df-a81d-efbc59784c66","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a test that incorrectly comes back negative","mBack":"false negative"},{"mId":"fd8e3d27-3e62-48b4-b2a5-369606dccaae","mCardType":"text","mFront":"medical background of a person\u0027s family members","mBack":"family history"},{"mId":"d7348651-72ed-4d2f-aa6b-99beecdc5598","mCardType":"text","mFront":"causing death","mBack":"fatal"},{"mId":"20ba1f65-1667-4053-99d0-cdf9c59c6a91","mCardType":"text","mFront":"higher than normal body temperature","mBack":"fever"},{"mId":"50281050-11ec-449f-8618-b558fce3f2d9","mCardType":"text","mFront":"many types of respiratory or intestinal infections passed on through a virus","mBack":"flu"},{"mId":"86a169a4-3d22-4000-bc3c-fb668f36c6f0","mCardType":"text","mFront":"broken or cracked bone","mBack":"fracture"},{"mId":"06155379-e727-4671-b6f9-5504314b9308","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a micro-organism, especially one that causes disease","mBack":"germ"},{"mId":"ddb753f1-fa08-49fe-87b8-50dc2f1e6b71","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a medical condition or physical feature that is passed on in the family","mBack":"genetic"},{"mId":"a58e3cbc-9062-4aec-8020-1975c6ecd614","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a ball of tissue that grows bigger than normal, either on or under the skin","mBack":"growth"},{"mId":"35b59c7e-71fd-4aab-a8be-5553b4d730f1","mCardType":"text","mFront":"instance in which blood stops pumping through the heart","mBack":"heart attack"},{"mId":"503d7263-5958-49fa-9084-431a92f64a23","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the virus that infects the human T-cells and leads to AIDS","mBack":"HIV"},{"mId":"5c264e44-6ff2-45ab-81ce-040c3d6e2d39","mCardType":"text","mFront":"bumps that appear on the surface of the skin during an allergic reaction","mBack":"hives"},{"mId":"c773f919-c149-45a8-be9c-908f031b12ff","mCardType":"text","mFront":"general term for any condition that makes a person feel sick for a certain period of time","mBack":"illness"},{"mId":"62ccf209-fcdd-4f9e-b171-c1b60bce3f64","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the parts of the body that fight diseases, infections, and viruses","mBack":"immune system"},{"mId":"d1260935-4358-47a3-a51a-1703b43e0124","mCardType":"text","mFront":"an injection that protects against a specific disease","mBack":"immunization"},{"mId":"8ec25f3d-4b97-4760-867c-ccea495f8328","mCardType":"text","mFront":"cut in the body made during surgery","mBack":"incision"},{"mId":"eed61a5a-31fd-4dc9-9086-956ccfe7e6ae","mCardType":"text","mFront":"unclear","mBack":"inconclusive"},{"mId":"5d23fcc2-c5b3-45c0-9818-8971e65b933c","mCardType":"text","mFront":"young baby","mBack":"infant"},{"mId":"e7ccc6df-3e0c-4a1d-bc59-471a4343433d","mCardType":"text","mFront":"diseased area of the body (viral or bacterial)","mBack":"infection"},{"mId":"9be2316c-22e1-487b-870d-0afbff16dce1","mCardType":"text","mFront":"appearance (red and swollen) of an injured body part","mBack":"inflamed"},{"mId":"5c8296e5-db56-4413-8217-0ee74eaf4416","mCardType":"text","mFront":"damage to the body","mBack":"injury"},{"mId":"d3756fb2-6214-49c8-8f7b-b793a7ca87f9","mCardType":"text","mFront":"under the skin, inside the organs","mBack":"internal"},{"mId":"6a83d28e-a606-49a4-9c21-a073d1a1b6e3","mCardType":"text","mFront":"feeling discomfort on the skin\u0027s surface","mBack":"itchy"},{"mId":"8ffedba6-6efa-4fa6-843a-cfcce0260040","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a tube that pumps liquids and medication into a patient\u0027s body","mBack":"IV"},{"mId":"0b313579-4b74-4033-9e47-a2434eff3497","mCardType":"text","mFront":"tests that come back from a laboratory and help doctors make a diagnosis","mBack":"lab results"},{"mId":"8f2d9957-1934-4075-9b00-8cba99ff087a","mCardType":"text","mFront":"place where samples of blood/urine etc. are taken for testing","mBack":"laboratory"},{"mId":"a4756dd8-c5dc-42f5-ac87-9e7cac11735c","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a machine that keeps patients alive by helping them breathe","mBack":"life support"},{"mId":"9397a0ef-1203-4f22-96c4-ce8e3c308e51","mCardType":"text","mFront":"when injuries and conditions are extremely serious","mBack":"life-threatening"},{"mId":"4f3b8a9d-927f-4f28-915c-d519476d0ee7","mCardType":"text","mFront":"feeling of dizziness and being off-balance, caused by lack of oxygen in the brain","mBack":"light-headed"},{"mId":"a40af5fc-ea43-49c1-a326-a9dfe33b2f64","mCardType":"text","mFront":"expected to grow and get much worse (especially related to cancerous cells)","mBack":"malignant"},{"mId":"87709a8b-ab92-4f05-92a9-155e0a38fff1","mCardType":"text","mFront":"place where someone trains to be a doctor","mBack":"medical school "},{"mId":"de3a0fc6-e4cf-403d-a738-5b5665f08fcf","mCardType":"text","mFront":"an infant that is less than three months old","mBack":"newborn"},{"mId":"b0ce9bf1-7e74-4048-95ac-ba57e3f35d6b","mCardType":"text","mFront":"no feeling in a certain body part","mBack":"numb"},{"mId":"525c9e24-64f3-424e-9265-62cd2cce8914","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the place where major surgeries and operations take place","mBack":"operating room"},{"mId":"a68ecf82-bd9d-456f-8dc4-76bdafbc652d","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a medical procedure that involves going inside a person\u0027s body in an attempt to fix a problem","mBack":"operation"},{"mId":"60784bfd-f356-4726-a852-766360b837d1","mCardType":"text","mFront":"strong discomfort in certain areas of the body","mBack":"pain"},{"mId":"0ceb8892-9e79-4f04-8686-546eb083abe0","mCardType":"text","mFront":"type of medicine that takes away some or all of the discomfort of an illness or injury","mBack":"pain killer"},{"mId":"b37c28f1-31a5-43d8-8b23-dd3f9450e5ef","mCardType":"text","mFront":"unable to move certain areas of the body","mBack":"paralyzed"},{"mId":"12c40f24-6ef9-4a84-9574-cd7c1ec35317","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a person staying in a hospital or medical facility","mBack":"patient"},{"mId":"9963a7c4-d61e-4c20-a894-dcc41cb2c388","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a person who fills a doctor\u0027s prescription and gives people advice about medication","mBack":"pharmacist"},{"mId":"e6b1ae46-0b12-4070-9d2b-cc1f531b6eff","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a place where people go to buy medication and other medical supplies","mBack":"pharmacy"},{"mId":"6a171224-1fd7-4dd6-b41b-1751a77a7548","mCardType":"text","mFront":"doctor","mBack":"physician"},{"mId":"21b5685c-408c-4539-9a8a-5853e483c4a5","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a substance that is very dangerous if it enters the human body","mBack":"poison"},{"mId":"d08c32f2-3783-42e4-a069-4fbf7bd7987b","mCardType":"text","mFront":"of the time period leading up to giving birth","mBack":"prenatal"},{"mId":"e9cb2dbb-35a6-4890-ac1e-d09d0f507784","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the correct amount and type of medication needed to cure an illness or relieve symptoms","mBack":"prescription"},{"mId":"ff6f0501-26ad-4c99-90b4-a24ff67adbe2","mCardType":"text","mFront":"being alone; personal (eg test results)","mBack":"privacy"},{"mId":"dbde7223-c22d-40dd-9031-323f34c5beb5","mCardType":"text","mFront":"high energy X-rays that destroy cancer cells","mBack":"radiation"},{"mId":"209e045a-c242-49ff-bee7-9c9317e92afc","mCardType":"text","mFront":"part of a doctor\u0027s training that takes place in the hospital","mBack":"residency"},{"mId":"614a0f1f-0e7b-44fe-b3d3-da52060d6882","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a doctor\u0027s appointment to check a person\u0027s general health","mBack":"routine check-up"},{"mId":"8cea3036-9d8f-48de-980e-f428a5911c5f","mCardType":"text","mFront":"plain uniform (usually green, white, or blue) worn by medical professionals","mBack":"scrubs"},{"mId":"30099d9a-890a-4625-8b36-25e1e69f8063","mCardType":"text","mFront":"carefully wash hands before and after seeing a patient","mBack":"scrub up"},{"mId":"d78fbf6a-142a-41ef-948c-47b3a14b6fa3","mCardType":"text","mFront":"input from a second doctor about an illness or symptom","mBack":"second opinion"},{"mId":"8006571b-9a0a-4c48-baac-786e00d267cf","mCardType":"text","mFront":"sudden violent movements or unconsciousness caused by electrical signal malfunction in the brain","mBack":"seizure"},{"mId":"d25ba13b-5fed-4b74-aa84-c016df0ee44f","mCardType":"text","mFront":"body not getting enough blood flow","mBack":"shock"},{"mId":"85ec50a7-da44-4796-82e3-c36d69b0bf3b","mCardType":"text","mFront":"other symptoms that might occur as a result of a certain medication or procedure","mBack":"side effects"},{"mId":"15e2bf55-22d8-448f-859a-409874f82ed4","mCardType":"text","mFront":"painful","mBack":"sore"},{"mId":"91ebda54-6174-43ea-8748-3c42db4adb62","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the uncontrollable tightening of a muscle","mBack":"spasm"},{"mId":"5cdacbc3-ec23-4c49-a950-d2b464f3639f","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a doctor that is an expert in a certain kind of medicine","mBack":"specialist"},{"mId":"30e98b4b-c75f-49b6-b1d0-0a5d248a7057","mCardType":"text","mFront":"an injury (less serious than a break) to a joint (ankle, wrist, knee etc)","mBack":"sprain"},{"mId":"802d6f47-4085-4c29-a295-73eb1bbb84b7","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a patient is stable if their medical condition is no longer changing rapidly","mBack":"stable condition"},{"mId":"7f4d6005-bef6-4b8e-9468-02b947d515e2","mCardType":"text","mFront":"sharp, temporary pain","mBack":"sting"},{"mId":"86ac9571-b2eb-4627-8d97-0582c4aa8bc0","mCardType":"text","mFront":"worry that causes muscles to tighten and blood pressure to rise","mBack":"stress"},{"mId":"d62a7329-e509-4dde-ac9f-5fbf73122d63","mCardType":"text","mFront":"ligaments (parts that hold the joints together) growing bigger and rounder after an injury to a joint","mBack":"swelling"},{"mId":"bf76f5a0-153f-47fe-a17b-f4491f4649a5","mCardType":"text","mFront":"pain or physical changes that occur because of an illness or disease","mBack":"symptoms"},{"mId":"21196981-5fa6-4775-ac47-5a57b68455de","mCardType":"text","mFront":"amount of heat measured in a body; higher than normal temperature","mBack":"temperature"},{"mId":"0ef3c5a5-5e8d-4a85-a4da-24312e3e31e3","mCardType":"text","mFront":"painful when touched or used","mBack":"tender"},{"mId":"6ba42001-8c62-452d-8b75-74aa5c9cb433","mCardType":"text","mFront":"medical information that helps doctors understand a patient\u0027s condition or body","mBack":"test results"},{"mId":"e27fa57d-366d-4a4b-9173-2e7629d6d4d9","mCardType":"text","mFront":"treatment aimed at improving a person\u0027s mental or physical condition","mBack":"therapy"},{"mId":"b416144e-78ac-4c4a-a884-d641987460f8","mCardType":"text","mFront":"moving of an organ from one human to another","mBack":"transplant"},{"mId":"935782be-22f8-4c35-a3c6-de10c8030578","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a test that examines the body\u0027s internal organs and processes using sound waves (often used during pregnancies)","mBack":"ultrasound"},{"mId":"31d97fd7-790c-4272-b061-0ad9f2f476a7","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the lifeline from the mother to the fetus (when cut at birth this forms the belly button)","mBack":"umbilical cord"},{"mId":"6b20c3c7-94b6-4a2a-80b6-05e208de9618","mCardType":"text","mFront":"alive, but appearing to be asleep and unaware of the surroundings","mBack":"unconscious"},{"mId":"7406704c-6b38-4c66-a3ae-f9401ef73659","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a small amount of the body\u0027s liquid waste that is tested for different medical reasons","mBack":"urine sample"},{"mId":"3045c95d-7bba-43ee-b48e-eb199f8c22ac","mCardType":"text","mFront":"the thin tubes that transport blood around the body and back to the heart","mBack":"vein"},{"mId":"d4fed9fd-6daf-46ef-ad9d-4f5b5366afa4","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a dangerous organism that causes the spread of minor and major diseases","mBack":"virus"},{"mId":"f3fb0b20-660e-4a97-b43f-88619735b99c","mCardType":"text","mFront":"time of day when friends and family are allowed to visit patients in hospital","mBack":"visiting hours"},{"mId":"d4f43bf1-58ee-4684-8450-d35d39671d9a","mCardType":"text","mFront":"discharge of a person stomach contents through the mouth","mBack":"vomit"},{"mId":"9c85f549-cd7b-4744-85b3-0698108c4ef5","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a section of a hospital or health facility where patients stay","mBack":"ward"},{"mId":"ab1e38d9-3831-4535-a17f-bbe3e840b8c3","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a chair on wheels used for transporting patients from place to place","mBack":"wheelchair"},{"mId":"017228d8-6a12-42c1-b9de-e18bf324da37","mCardType":"text","mFront":"injury to body (\"flesh wound\" means not deep)","mBack":"wound"},{"mId":"a53b3af4-4782-4a3f-b0c6-004330198e3c","mCardType":"text","mFront":"a photograph of a person\u0027s bones and organs","mBack":"x-ray"}]}